<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>danieljohnevans</title>
        <description>danieljohnevans - </description>
        <link>http://danieljohnevans.github.io</link>
        <link>http://danieljohnevans.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2015-04-20T15:01:19-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2015-04-20T15:01:19-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>A Year in Review</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved to Somerville from the North Shore in September. While I’m still working on the North Shore, my commute has invariably risen from a seemingly quick 30 minute car ride to a 1.5 to 2 hour subway-to-commuter-rail marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve started reading. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since January 2014, I’ve read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bukowski, Charles 
    Hot Water Music
Carver, Raymond 
    Cathedral
    What We Talk About When We Talk About Love
Dumas, Alexandre 
    The Count of Monte Cristo
Ellis, Bret Easton 
    American Psycho
Fariña, Richard 
    Been Down So Long it Looks Like Up to Me
Hajdu, David 
    Positively 4th Street: The Lives and Times of Joan Baez, Bob Dylan, Mimi Baez Fariña, and Richard Fariña
Hemingway, Ernest 
    The Old Man and the Sea
    The Sun Also Rises
Ilgunas, Ken 
    Walden on Wheels: On the Open Road from Debt to Freedom
Johnson, Denis 
    Tree of Smoke
Kerouac, Jack 
    Tristessa
Lahiri, Jhumpa 
    The Namesake
Lampedusa, Giuseppe Tomasi di 
    The Leopard
McCarthy, Cormac 
    Blood Meridian, or the Evening Redness in the West
McMurtry, Larry 
    Lonesome Dove
Millard, Candice 
    The River of Doubt: Theodore Roosevelt’s Darkest Journey
    Destiny of the Republic: A Tale of Madness, Medicine and the Murder of a President
Mitchell, Joseph 
    Up in the Old Hotel
Munro, Alice 
    Dear Life: Stories
    Runaway
Piketty, Thomas 
    Capital in the Twenty-First Century
Salter, James 
    A Sport and a Pastime
Saunders, George 
    Tenth of December
    CivilWarLand in Bad Decline
Tower, Wells 
    Everything Ravaged, Everything Burned
Wood, Pamela 
    The Salt Book: Lobstering, Sea Moss Pudding, Stone Walls, Rum Running, Maple Syrup, Snowshoes, and Other Yankee Doings
Zweig, Stefan 
    Beware of Pity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I’ve read most of these books this fall. I loved Candice Millard’s writing style. I’ve recommended her to a few friends and even those who aren’t usually fans of popular history are really blown away by her captivating style. I was pleasantly surprised to see her interviewed on Ken Burns’ Roosevelts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that I should also note that I’ve gone on a bit of a short story kick. I literally could not put down Carver, Munro and Saunders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not recorded here are the countless times I spent picking up, and putting down, &lt;code&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/code&gt;. I just can’t seem to commit to that book. I feel like I’ll pick it up and get into it only to read a review or receive a recommendation and drop it for something more approachable. There’s so many other things I’m dying to read. Maybe I’ll go on a media blackout in 2015 and just force myself through it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://danieljohnevans.github.io/about/2015/01/02/books-in-review</link>
                <guid>http://danieljohnevans.github.io/about/2015/01/02/books-in-review</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-01-02T12:09:50-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Welcome</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This site has been in the making for awhile now. Actually it lived and died in Wordpress for a brief period last fall and is finally live via Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using this blog to record my thoughts and projects specifically as they relate to my explorations in digital history. I think it’ll be useful to have a place to write down my blunders and (hopefully) get feedback from the larger DH community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best –&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://danieljohnevans.github.io/about/2015/01/01/welcome</link>
                <guid>http://danieljohnevans.github.io/about/2015/01/01/welcome</guid>
                <pubDate>2015-01-01T12:09:50-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
